#### **Archan Thakur**

Flat No. H1/B/8/16, Lakeview Housing Complex, /1A Drainage Canal Road, Howrah-711104, West Bengal

Indian nationality, married +919028207580 | thakur.archan@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

An HR solution expert, with 18 plus years of experience in the areas of HR Transformation, Product management, Presales and Project management. SAP certified HCM and SuccessFactors solution consultant with exposure to CRM, MDG, Financials and Business Intelligence solutions. Focused on business technology issues and business value of IT applications.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE Wipro Ltd.

#### **Managing Consultant- HR Transformation**

Jun 2022- today, Kolkata

- Delivering end to end HR Transformation for global organizations
- Process Analysis and "To be" process design for HR processes
- HR technology System Landscape analysis and "To" be landscape design
- Delivery of Solution Design and Functional Design document as HR solution Architect

#### **Principal Consultant -Presales**

Jun 2020- Jun 2022, Bangalore

- Working closely with the USA/Europe/MEA/Australia sales teams on HR solution proposals as presales lead for SAP HCM and SF solution team
- Solution and Bid Management for HR Application Management Services and HR Transformation programs
- Responding to RFI and RFQ
- Closed Deal Values: 1 million USD to 5 million USD

### Utopia India Pvt. Ltd. Manager -Presales

Sept 2019- June 2020, Bangalore

 Presales/ Bid Management for SAP MDG solution and Data lifecycle management / Data strategy services

# IBM Global Business Services Solution Architect(Presales)- SAP SuccessFactors

Aug 2017- Aug 2019, Bangalore

- Worked closely with the IBM India & South east Asia (ISA) sales team on proposals and pitches for SAP S4HANA HCM and SAP SuccessFactors solution
- Facilitated customer discovery and implementation scoping sessions to define requirements for input to implementation plans, estimates, resource models
- Created formal services proposals, RFP responses and Statement of Work (SOW)

#### **SAP India**

#### **Presales Solution Specialist**

#### October 2015 - July 2017, Bangalore/Singapore

**Deal Support:** 

 Presented value-based SAP SuccessFactors and SAP HCM solution demo to diverse range of stakeholders in India & APJ in support of sales cycles.

#### Bramasol Inc.

#### Manager (Presales) –SAP Cloud and HANA solutions

**January 2013 – Sept 2015, Pune** 

- Pre Sales and Marketing support to sales team for SAP solutions like SuccessFactors, SAP
   HCM, SRM, HANA migration, HANA Live etc for India and USA market.
- Management of a cross functional teams focused on SAP HANA and other SAP Cloud Solutions like SAP Business By Design
- Management of new innovative product development based on SAP HANA
- Create and execute the project plan as the assigned project manager for SAP Business ByDesign Projects

## SAP LABS INDIA Principal Consultant – Product Management

India / Germany Feb 2006 – Sept 2011

#### Responsibilities:

- Gathered market requirements and launched new SAP HCM and SAP BusinessByDesign solutions in different countries e.g. India, China, UK, Austria, Canada, Brazil.
- Conducted market development activities such as solution demonstrations/workshop etc. for the newly developed solutions and participated in events such as SAP World Tour
- Supported sales and implementation teams as a product expert by participating in client visits and on-site solution demo and consultation
- Designed product strategy by analysing and market positioning of SAP solutions in collaboration with partner solutions
- Actively participated in implementation of "Lean" software development model in the organization and executed the role of "Product Owner "
- Managed 2 project teams composed of globally distributed team members

#### IFS India

#### **Functional Consultant**

July 2004 - Jan 2006

• Implemented IFS [ERP software product] Human Resource solution @ HAL (3 divisions)

#### **Qualifications**

Master of Business Administration (MBA),
 Durham Business School, United Kingdom

June 2002 - June 2004

 MBA( Systems ) ICFAI Business School, India

August 1996 - June 2000

B.TECH (Computer Systems)
 OUBC Canada, Aptech-India
 B.A., Philosophy, Film Studies

August 1996 - July 1999

Sept 2011 – Aug 2012

 B.A., Philosophy, Film Studies Jadavpur University, India